

User focused developer with over 20 years of experience developing websites and web applications. I've been creating online software using the .NET Framework and ASP.NET MVC 5 for the past 10 years.

Top Skills: C#/.NET Framework, ASP.NET MVC 5, Angular, React, Vue, Javascript, CSS/SASS, MSSQL

## **Employment**

## Contract Software Developer Feb. 2019 - Present

#### Zolon Tech, Inc. / Defense Media Activity

- Developed and maintained websites for the Department of Defense: defense.gov, usace.army.mil, marines.mil, navy.mil, and more.
- Developed new E-Publishing module for the Air Force using C# and Vue JS
- Utilized C#, JavaScript, SASS, and Vue JS to build and maintain modules for the DNN content management system

#### Sycorr, Inc / Bank of North Dakota

- Worked with loan officers and banking experts to create an automated system for billing and processing commercial loans.
- Created using .NET Framework, ASP.NET MVC 5, MSSQL Server, Razor templates, AngularJS and jQuery.
- Created automated deposit files, MS Excel reports and emails using Quartz.
- Created over 900 unit tests during development to ensure system integrity with sensitive financial data.

## Sycorr, Inc / MHA Nation Department of Transportation

- Developed the online system for licensing commercial trucks and issuing permits for travel and oil drilling on MHA Nation land.
- Created using .NET Framework, ASP.NET MVC 5, MSSQL Server, Razor templates, AngularJS and jQuery.
- Developed their online payment system for paying permit and license fees using Authrorize.NET APIs.

# **Sycorr, Inc** Jan. 2013 - Jan. 2019

#### Senior Software Developer

- Principal front-end developer for many .NET Framework web applications in the financial sector.
- Coordinated custom jQuery and AngularJS front-ends with ASP.NET MVC 5 backend development.
- My front-end work allowed the company to rapidly develop enterprise applications.
- Helped create the company's flagship identity auditing software for banks.

## Idea Bank Marketing Feb. 2007 - Dec. 2013

#### Lead Web Developer

- Responsible for developing over 25 marketing websites and web applications.
- Worked with senior management and led a team of 3 developers to complete projects on budget and on time.
- Developed the online storefront for the largest privately owned ammunition manufacturer in the world.
- Technologies included PHP, MODx, JavaScript, SASS/LESS and AngularJS.

## **Education**

**Bachelor of Fine Arts** - Emphasis in Printmaking Kansas City Art Institute, Kansas City, MO, 2001

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

## Comptia Security+

Issued May 2020

#### **Certificate of Graduation**

Dakota School of Banking - Jamestown, ND June 2014 to June 2015

## **Comprehensive Skill Set**

## 10+ yrs professional experience

- C#
- .NET Framework 4.7.2
- Razor Templating
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- MSSQL
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SASS
- LESS
- Bootstrap
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Agile Methodologies
- Test Driven Development
- XUnit
- NUnit
- Git
- Atlassian Stack
- Windows, Mac, Linux

## 5+ yrs professional experience

- AngularJS
- Vue
- Node
- PHP
- MySQL, MSSQL
- DNN CMS
- Wordpress
- MODx CMS
- TypeScript
- WCAG Accessibility
- Material Design
- Github
- REST and SOAP APIs
- Authorize.NET and other payment gateway APIs

## 3+ yrs experience

- .NET Core
- React
- React Native
- Redux
- WPF
- C/C++
- Embedded Programming
- Bluetooth Development
- ATMega and Renesas
  Microcontrollers
- CAD Software